Guide to the Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection AIA.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection
1811-2025
1964-2010
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America
Benson, James A.
Prendiville, Sean
McGrady, Conor
Powner, Mary Lou
AIA.004
236.25 Linear Feet in 13 record cartons, 31 manuscript boxes, 3 half manuscript boxes, 4 flat file folders, 210 oversize flat boxes, 7 folders in shared housing, and 4 folders in 2 oversized shared boxes
The materials in this collection were collected and assembled by archives staff and various donors in an attempt to document the variety of newspapers and other publications produced by and for the Irish American community. It consists of major runs of several prominent Irish American newspapers and periodicals, ranging from general interest weekly newspapers to more narrowly focused, overtly political publications. The collection's major runs include An Phoblacht / Republican News (1906-present), the official organ of Sinn Féin; Irish Echo (1964-present); Irish People (1972-2004); Irish Voice (1987-2003). The explicitly political publications focus mostly on Irish republicanism and conflict in Northern Ireland.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Received from Archives of Irish America staff, Consulate General of Ireland, The Irish Bookshop, Cherry Lane Productions, Marion Casey, Linda Dowling Almeida, Mary Lou Powner, Conor McGrady, and Cormac K.H. O'Malley in multiple installments, beginning in 1996. The Nation and Spirit of Freedom included in donations from Sean Prendiville and George Harrison. 19th-century newspapers donated by Sean Prendiville.
Accession number associated with this collection include 1997.007, 1997.018, 1997.059, 2000.025, 2011.005, 2011.027, 2018.096, 2019.099, and 2021.020.
Additional accretions were donated by Marion Casey in 2018 and 2019. The accession numbers associated with these accretions are 2018.096 and 2019.099.
Two issues of Glór Na Saoirse were removed from the George Harrison Papers (AIA 009) during processing in August 2020 and transferred to this collection; the accession number associated with this accretion is 2021.020.
Several newspapers and magazines were removed from the Jack O'Brien Papers (AIA.067) and the Kevin Kennedy Ephemera and Photographs Collection (AIA.063) and transferred to this collection in 2021.
An accretion of issues of The Recorder was donated in November 2024 by Ann Garvey as part of her and her late husband's personal papers collection (AIA 088). These materials were appraised out of the collection and transferred to AIA 004 on advice of the curator.
In March 2025, Marion Casey donated an accretion of holdings from multiple publications; the accession number associated with this transfer is 2025.042.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series:
Series I: Newspapers, 1836-2020
Series II: Other Publications, 1881-2019
Within each series, materials are arranged alphabetically by title, thereunder chronologically.
Historical Note
The materials in this collection were collected and assembled by archives staff and various donors in an attempt to document the variety of newspapers and other publications produced by and for the Irish American community.
Related Materials
Related collections at the Tamiment Library include the George Harrison Papers (AIA.009), the Irish Republicanism Collection (AIA.022), the Cormac K. H. O'Malley Papers (AIA.019), the Patrick Daughton Collection (AIA.055), the Ernie O'Malley Papers (AIA.060), the Jack O'Brien Papers (AIA.067), and the Kevin Kennedy Ephemera and Photographs Collection (AIA.063).
The newspaper Irish People has been digitized and is available through the website of the Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis University Library.
Other copies of the newspaper The Advocate can be found in NYU's library catalog, Bobcat.
Scope and Contents
The Archives of Irish America Newspaper and Periodicals Collections is an intentionally assembled collection of various newspapers and other publications published by and for the Irish American community. It consists of major runs of several prominent Irish American newspapers and periodicals, ranging from general interest weekly newspapers to more narrowly focused, overtly political publications. The explicitly political publications focus mostly on Irish republicanism and conflict in Northern Ireland.
The collection's major runs include An Phoblacht / Republican News (1906-present), the official organ of Sinn Féin; Irish Echo (1964-present); and Irish People (1972-2004). Also included are regional publications like the Boston Irish News, the Irish American Press from Southern California, and The Tablet from Brooklyn and Queens, New York. Although the majority of the collection dates from the late 20th-century, a few 19th-century papers are present, including the Irish Citizen (1871-1897), Green Banner (1836), and Shamrock (1811).
Of note in the periodicals series are issues of The Nation, published by the Irish American Defense Fund; Spirit of Freedom, an Irish American publication in support of republicanism in Northern Ireland; Irish America, a magazine focusing on the Irish in America and famous Americans of Irish heritage; Ireland of the Welcomes, the official publication of the Ireland Tourist Board; and An Gaodhal, a bi-lingual magazine concerning art, music, and the Irish language.
Separated Materials
Issues of The Advocate and The Irish Voice have been transferred to the library collection (call numbers HD6510 .A34 and F128.9.I6 I65 respectively).
Sunburst: A Journal of Irish Literature was separated for bibliographic cataloging.
Newspapers.; England.; Magazines (Periodicals); Periodicals; Chicago (Ill.); Journals (periodicals); San Francisco (Calif.); Irish Americans -- Periodicals.; Irish Americans -- Newspapers.; Irish Americans -- New York (State) -- New York -- Periodicals.; Irish Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- Newspapers.; Nation (New York, N.Y.: 1865); Irish Americans -- Massachusetts -- Boston -- Newspapers.; Irish Americans -- New York (State) -- Newspapers.; Irish echo (New York, N.Y.); Irish voice (New York, N.Y.); Irish people (New York, N.Y.)$2local; Irish America; Irish voice (New York, N.Y.); Spirit of Freedom; World of Hibernia; The Irish people; Benson, James A.; Prendiville, Sean; McGrady, Conor; Powner, Mary Lou; Irish echo
- Series I: Newspapers, 1836-2020; 211.5 Linear Feet in 6 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 4 flat file folders, and 204 oversized boxes
  Scope and Contents
  The materials in this series consist of major runs of several prominent Irish American newspapers, ranging from general interest weekly newspapers to more narrowly focused, overtly political publications. The collection's major runs include An Phoblacht/Republican News (1906-present), the official organ of Sinn Féin; Irish Echo (1964-present); and the Irish People (1972-2004).
  - American Record, 1975; cuid14561 (Box 144)
    Vol. 1, No. 1; Vol. 11 Mar 17, 1975; May – Jun, 1975; Jul 4, 1975
  - An Phoblacht / Republican News (Dublin), 1981-1994; cuid14546 (Box 169)
    Jun 1981, Mar 1984-Jan 1986, Jan 1989-Jun 1994 (with gaps)
  - An Phoblacht / Republican News (Dublin), 1993-1997; cuid14547 (Box 193, Box 170, Box 171)
    Nov 1993, 1994 (except Jan), 1995, 1996, Jan-Jun 1997
  - An Phoblacht / Republican News (Dublin), 1997-2006; cuid14551 (Box 172, Box 173, Box 174)
    Jul 1997 - Dec 1998, 1999-2000 (with gaps), 2001-2006 (with gaps)
  - An Phoblacht / Republican News (Dublin), 1980-2017 (Box 225, Folder 1-6)
    Mar 1980; Apr 1980; Sept 1994; Mar 1995; July 1996; Nov 2002; Jun 2003; Oct 2003; Aug-Oct 2008; July-Dec 2010; Oct-Dec 2012; Apr 2013; June 2013; Aug 2013; Aug 2015; Mar-May 2016; Apr-Nov 2017
  - The Boston Irish News, 1986–1990; cuid14562 (Box 146, Box 222, Folder 10)
  - Catholic News, Oct 1979 (Box 220, Folder 7)
  - Catholic New York, 1984, 1990, 1994, 1996, 2000; cuid14563 (Box 144, Box 223, Folder 1-2)
    Mar 1996 - Vol. 15, No. 26; Feb 2 1984; Mar 22 1984; Apr 19 1990; Mar 10 1994; Jan 13 2000; May 2000
  - Celtic Connection: Vol. 1, No. 3, Dec 1991, Jan 1992; cuid14564 (Box 144)
  - Celtic Mirror / An Scathan: Vol. 1, Nos. 1, 8, Vol. 3, No. 12, Mar 1995–Feb 1998; cuid14565 (Box 144)
  - Celtic Weekly, Mar 1872–Sep 1873; cuid14566 (Box 147)
  - The Citizen, Mar 1998; cuid14567 (Box 193)
  - Clan-na-Gael Journal (Philadelphia), Aug 5, 1895; Jun 27, 1915; cuid14568 (Box Shared Tamiment 175, Folder 16-17)
  - The Desert Shamrock, Nov-Dec 1997 (Box 222, Folder 11)
  - Fenian News, Vol. 2 and 3, 1930-1931; cuid14569 (Box Shared Tamiment 169, Folder 23)
  - Florida Irish–American, Nov 1990, Oct 1996, Dec 1996, March 1997; cuid14570 (Box 144, Box 223, Folder 4)
  - Fortnight, Nov 1971–Dec 1971; cuid14571 (Box 144)
  - Gael, Jul 1998; cuid14572 (Box 144)
  - Globe and Emerald (New York) Vol. 2, No. 11, 1825; cuid14573 (Box 149)
  - Glór Na Saoirse, 1972 (Box 184, Folder 5)
  - Green Banner, 1836; cuid14574 (Box 148)
  - The Harvard Crimson, Nov 23, 1963; cuid14575 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Ireland Digest (Dublin), May 1986; cuid14576 (Box 145)
  - Irish American News, 1995; cuid14918 (Box 208, Folder 2)
  - Irish American Post, Apr 1992–Apr 2001; cuid14577 (Box 149, Box 220, Folder 15)
  - Irish American Post, 1992-1994 (Box 222, Folder 1-3)
    Apr 1992 Vol 1 No 1; May 1992 Vol 1 No 2; Jun 1992 Vol 1 No 3; July 1992 Vol 1 No 4; Aug 1992 Vol 1 No 5; Sept 1992 Vol 1 No 6; Oct 1992 Vol 1 No 7; Nov 1992 Vol 1 No 8; Dec 1992 Vol 1 No 9; April 1993 Vol 2 No 1; May 1993 Vol 2 No 2; June 1993 Vol 2 No 3; July 1993 Vol 2 No 4; Aug 1993 Vol 2 No 5; Jan/Feb 1994; Mar 1994; May 1994 Vol 3 No 3; June 1994 Vol 3 No 4; July 1994 Vol 3 No 5; Aug 1994 Vol 3 No 6; Aug 1994
  - Irish American Press (Southern CA), Jul 1989–Nov 1991; cuid14578 (Box 144)
  - Irish American Review (St. Louis, MO), Mar 1987; cuid14579 (Box 144)
  - Irish Arts Center Newsletter, Oct 1992–Oct 1994; cuid14580 (Box 144)
  - Irish Citizen, 1867 October-1871 July; cuid14581 (Box 150)
  - The Irish Daily Mail, 2017 (Box 220, Folder 13)
  - Irish Democrat (London) (with gaps), Jan 1984–Jul 1988, Feb 2002-Nov 2005, 2005-2007; cuid14582 (Box 145, Box 220, Folder 16)
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1929; cuid14914 (Box Shared Tamiment AIAXOS001, Folder 1)
  - Irish Echo (New York) (BRITTLE), Sept 19, 1942 (Box Shared Tamiment 149, Folder 7)
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1945 (Box Shared Tamiment 187, Folder 23)
    May 26, 1945; June 9, 1945
  - Irish Echo (New York) (BRITTLE), Mar 26, 1960 (Box 236, Folder 1)
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1964-1974; cuid14583 (Box 8, Box 9, Box 10)
    Nov 28, 1964; 1966 Easter Rising 50th Anniversary Supplement; Dec 13, 1969; Jul 24, 1971; Apr 22, 1972; Feb 24, 1973; Mar 3, 1973-Dec 29, 1973; Jan 5, 1974-Dec 28, 1974
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1975-1979; cuid14586 (Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14)
    Jan 24, 1975-Sep 13, 1975; Sep 20, 1975-Dec 27, 1975; Jan 10-Sep 25, 1976; Oct 20, 1976-Dec 25, 1976; Jan 1, 1977-Jun 25, 1977; Jul 2, 1977-Oct 2, 1977; Jan 14, 1978-Dec 30, 1978; Jan 13, 1979-Mar 31, 1979
  - Irish Echo (New York) (BRITTLE), Jun 24, 1978 (Box 236, Folder 2)
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1979-1983; cuid14590 (Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19)
    Apr 7, 1979-Nov 24, 1979; Jan 5, 1980-Apr 26, 1980; May 3, 1980-Oct 18, 1980; Oct 25, 1980-Dec 27, 1980; Jan 3, 1981-Apr 4, 1981; Sep 4, 1982-Dec 25, 1982; Jan 1, 1983-Apr 30, 1983
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1979, 1984, 1990-1991, 1993 (Box 236, Folder 3-6)
    Jan 13 1979; Mar 10 1979; Mar 31 1979; Apr 28 1979; Sept 15 1979; Sept 22 1979; Sept 29 1979; Oct 6 1979; Oct 13 1979; Sept 22 1984; Jan 6 1990; Mar 3 1990; Jun 20-26 1990; Jun 27-July 3 1990; Feb 13-19 1991; Aug 21-27 1991; Aug 28-Sept 3 1991; Dec 4-10 1991; Sept 15-21 1993
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1983-1986; cuid14595 (Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25)
    May 7, 1983-Dec 31, 1983; Jan 7, 1984-Aug 25, 1984; Sep 1, 1984-Dec 29, 1984; Jan 5, 1985-Mar 16, 1985; Mar 22, 1985-Oct 26, 1985; Nov 2, 1985-Dec 25, 1985; Jan 4, 1986-May 24, 1986; May 31, 1986-Dec 27, 1986
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1987-1989; cuid14601 (Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30)
    Jan 3, 1987-Jul 18, 1987; Jul 25, 1987-Dec 26, 1987; Jan 2, 1988-May 5, 1988; May 21, 1988-Sep 17, 1988; Sep 24, 1988-Dec 31, 1988; Jan 7, 1989-Mar 4, 1989
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1989-1991; cuid14606 (Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35)
    Mar 11, 1989-Jul 1, 1989; Jul 8, 1989-Dec 30, 1989; Jan 13, 1990-May 29, 1990; May 30, 1990-Oct 16, 1990; Oct 25, 1990-Mar 26, 1991
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1991-1993; cuid14611 (Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39, Box 40)
    Mar 27, 1991-Nov 12, 1991; Nov 13, 1991-Dec 31, 1991; Jan 1, 1992-May 26, 1992; Jun 2, 1992-Dec 29, 1992; Dec 30, 1992-Jun 8, 1993; Jun 9, 1993-Oct 26, 1993
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1993-1995; cuid14616 (Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 44)
    Oct 27, 1993-Mar 8, 1994; Mar 9, 1994-May 15, 1994; May 18, 1994-Sep 27, 1994; Sep 28, 1994-Jan 3, 1995
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1994, 1998, 2001, 2004-2005, 2007-2008 (Box 237, Folder 1-4)
    Aug 24-30 1994; Sept 7-13 1994; July 1-7 1998; Sept 12-18 2001; Mar 10-16 2004; Mar 17-23 2004; May 19-25 2004; Aug 11-17 2004; Mar 16-22 2005; Aug 3-9 2005; Sept 28-Oct 4 2005; Nov 9-15 2005; Dec 5-11 2007; Dec 19-25 2007; Dec 26 2007-Jan 1 2008; Jan 2-8 2008; Jan 16-Feb 12 2008
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1995; cuid14620 (Box 45, Box 46, Box 47, Box 48)
    Jan 4, 1995-Mar 15, 1995; Mar 22, 1995-Jun 28, 1995; Jul 5, 1995-Sep 20, 1995; Oct 4, 1995-Dec 27, 1995
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1996-1998; cuid14624 (Box 49, Box 50, Box 51, Box 52, Box 53, Box 54)
    Jan 3, 1996-May 1, 1996; May 8, 1996-Aug 14, 1996; Aug 21, 1996-Dec 25, 1996; Jan 8, 1997-May 17, 1997; May 28, 1997-Oct 28, 1997; Oct 29, 1997-Dec 24, 1997; Jan 1, 1998-Mar 24, 1998
  - Irish Echo (New York), 1998-2000; cuid14630 (Box 55, Box 56, Box 57, Box 58, Box 59, Box 60)
    Mar 25, 1998-Aug 11, 1998; Aug 12, 1998-Dec 23, 1998; Jan 6, 1998-Jun 1, 1999; Jun 2, 1999-Dec 28, 1999; Dec 29, 1999-May 17, 2000; May 24, 2000-Oct 4, 2000
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2000-2002; cuid14636 (Box 61, Box 62, Box 63, Box 64, Box 65)
    Oct 11, 2000-Dec 27, 2000; Jan 3, 2001-Mar 7, 2001; Mar 14, 2001-Jul 18, 2001; Jul 25, 2001-Dec 26, 2001; Jan 9, 2002-May 15, 2002; May 22, 2002-Oct 9, 2002
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2002-2003, 2006-2008; cuid14641 (Box 66, Box 67, Box 68A, Box 68B, Box 68C, Box 68D)
    Oct 16, 2002-Dec 25, 2002; Jan 8, 2003-Feb 25, 2003; Feb 26, 2003-Jul 22, 2003; Jul 23, 2003-Dec 9, 2003; 2006-2007; 2007-2008
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2008-2010, 2016; cuid14647 (Box 177, Box 178, Box 179, Box 209, Folder 7-8, Box 238, Folder 1-5, Box Shared Tamiment 198, Folder 5)
    Feb 20-Mar 4 2008; Mar 12-25 2008; Mar 26-April 15 2008; April 23-May 6 2008; May 7-June 10 2008; Jun 11-July 8 2008; Jul 2008-Nov 2008; Nov 2008-Mar 2009; Mar 2009-May 2010; June 2-8 2010; Sept 15-21 2010; Mar 16-22 2016; Mar 30-April 5 2016; April 6-12 2016; April 20-26 2016; April 27-May 3 2016
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2011-2016; cuid14650 (Box 186, Box 208, Folder 9, Box 209, Folder 6-7, Box 187, Box 211, Box 212)
    2011-2014; Feb 2015-Jun 2015; July 2015-Jan 2016
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2016-2018; cuid14916 (Box 208, Folder 6-8, Box 209, Folder 1-5, Box 210, Folder 1-6, Box 213, Box 214)
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2017-2019 (Box 215, Box 216, Box 217, Box 218)
    Feb-Aug 2017; Jan-Jun 2018; July-Nov 2018; Dec 2018-Apr 2019; May-Aug 2019
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2020 (Box 240, Folder 1-4)
    Mar 18-24, Aug 11-Sept 1, Sept 22-28, Nov 4-10
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2021 (Box 240, Folder 5-7)
    Oct 6-Dec 7
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2022 (Box 240, Folder 8-9, Box 241, Folder 1-7, Box 242, Folder 1-5)
    Jan 19-May 10, May 18-July 5, July 27-Sept 6, Sept 14-27, Oct 5-Nov 8, Nov 16-Dec 6
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2023 (Box 242, Folder 6-9, Box 243, Folder 1-9, Box 244, Folder 1)
    Jan 25-28, Apr 15-May 9, May 31- Sept 26, Oct 4-Oct 24, Nov 8-28, Dec 13, 2023-Jan 2, 2024
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2024 (Box 244, Folder 1-8, Box 245, Folder 1-7)
    Dec 13, 2023-Jan 2, 2024; Jan 10-Apr 30, May 22-Jul 16, Jul 31-Aug 6, Aug 21-Nov 19, Dec 4-31
  - Irish Echo (New York), 2025 (Box 245, Folder 8, Box Shared Tamiment 198, Folder 6-7)
    Jan 1-7, Jan 15-Feb 11- Mar 4
  - Irish Echo Boston Edition, 1986-1988; cuid14652 (Box 69, Box 70)
    Jan 25, 1986–Dec 27, 1986; Jan 3, 1987 – Aug 29, 1987; May 7, 1988–May 14, 1988
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA), 1984-2000, 2003-2011; cuid14654 (Box 71, Box 72, Box 73, Box 182)
    1984-1985; Feb 1986–Jul 1986; Jun 1989–Dec 1989; Jan 1990; May 1990; Jan 1991 [Vol. 4, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 8,9,11), Vol. 5, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 9,10), Vol. 6 Nos. 2-7 (Missing 1,4,6), Vol. 9, Nos. 6-12 (Missing 1-5), Vol. 10, Nos. 1,5, Vol. 11, No. 1]; Apr 1993; Jun 1993; Nov 1993; 1994-1996 [Vol. 13, Nos. 4,6,11, Vol. 14, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 2,3,7,9), Vol. 15, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 6,11), Vol. 16, Nos. 1-12, (Missing 2,4,10)]; Jan 1997-Jan 2000 [Vol. 17, Nos. 1-12 (Missing 5,11), Vol. 18, Nos. 2-12 (Missing 1,5,9), Marked Vol. 18, Nos. 12, 2-12, Vol. 20, No. 1]; Aug 2003; Jun 2008-Oct 2011 (with gaps)
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA), 1987-2017 (Box 226, Folder 1-6)
    July 4 1987; Aug-Sept 1987; Sept 1988; Mar 1990; Mar 1991; July-Aug 1991; Jan-Apr 1993; Jun 1993; Aug-Sept 1993; Nov-Dec 1993; Feb-Mar 1994; July 1994; Sept 1994; Oct 1996; May 1997; Nov 1997; Jan 1998; Aug 2007; Nov 2007; Mar-May 2008; Sept 2008; Mar 2009; May-July 2009; Sept 2009; Nov-Dec 2009; Aug-Sept 2011; Oct 2015, Feb-May 2016, April-May 2017
  - Irish Edition (Wyndmoor, PA), 2021 (Box 247, Folder 9)
    Sept 2021; Oct 2021
  - The Irish Emigrant, 1994–2001, 2006-2010, 2017, 2019; cuid14658 (Box 151, Box 221, Folder 7-10)
    1994–2001; 2006; Oct 15-21 2007; Nov 19-25 2007; 2008-2009; Mar 10-16 2008; Mar 17-23 2008; April 14-20 2008; April 21-27 2008; April 28-May 4 2008; July 13-19 2009; Sept 28-Oct 4 2009; Nov 2-8 2009; Dec 28 2009-Jan 3 2010; Jan 4-10 2010; Jan 11-17 2010; Jan 25-Jan 31 2010; Mar 27 2017; April 15, 2019
  - The Irish Examiner (New York), 2006-2008, 2010-2011 (Box 223, Folder 3, Box 175, Box 176)
    Mar 15-21 2006; Sept 13-19 2006; May 16-May 22 2007; Oct 10-16 2007; Mar 12-Mar 18 2008; Jun-Nov 2010; Nov 2010-May 2011
  - Irish Eyes (with gaps), 1994-1995, 2002; cuid14661 (Box 145, Box 220, Folder 10, Box 222, Folder 12)
    April 1994 Vol 1 No 5; Oct 1994 Vol 2 No 2, 1995; July 2002
  - Irish Gazette, 1998-2004; cuid14917 (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - Irish Herald (San Francisco, CA), 1974-2003; cuid14662 (Box 152, Box 153, Box 208, Folder 4-5)
  - The Irish Literary Supplement (Selden, NY), 1983-1992, 1994-2004; cuid14664 (Box 154)
  - Irishman (San Francisco, CA), Dec 1984–Mar 1989; cuid14665 (Box 145)
  - The Irish News, 2017 (Box 220, Folder 12)
  - Irish People (includes Supplement of Nov. 23, 1867), Jan 1868–May 1876; cuid14666 (Box 155)
  - Irish People (New York), 1972-1975; cuid14667 (Box 74, Box 75, Box 76, Box 77, Box 219, Folder 3)
    Jul 1972-Dec 1972; Jan 1973-Mar 1973; Mar 31, 1973-Dec 29, 1973; Jan 5, 1974-Aug 10, 1974; Aug 17, 1974-Dec 28, 1974; Jan 4, 1975-Oct 18, 1975
  - Irish People (New York), 1973-1977 (Box 221, Folder 1-4)
    Nov 24 1973; Mar 15 1975; Aug 16 1975; Sept 20 1975; Oct 4 1975; Oct 25 1975; Nov 1 1975; Nov 8 1975; Nov 15 1975; Nov 22 1975; Nov 29 1975; Dec 13 1975; Dec 20 1975; Dec 27 1975; Jan 3 1976; Jan 10 1976; Aug 21 1976; Oct 16 1976; July 9 1977; Jan 3 1976; Jan 10 1976; Aug 21 1976; Oct 16 1976; July 9 1977
  - Irish People (New York), 1976-1980; cuid14671 (Box 78, Box 79, Box 80, Box 81, Box 82, Box 219, Folder 3)
    Jan 24, 1976-Dec 18, 1976; Jan 1, 1977-Jul 16, 1977; Jul 23, 1977-Dec 24, 1977; Jan 7, 1978-Apr 8, 1978; Apr 15, 1978-Dec 23, 1978; Jan 6, 1979-Mar 17, 1979; Mar 24, 1979-Dec 22, 1979; Jan 12, 1980-Oct 18, 1980
  - Irish People (New York), 1980-1982; cuid14676 (Box 83, Box 84, Box 85, Box 86)
    Oct 25, 1980-Dec 20, 1980; Jan 1, 1981-Sep 18, 1981; Sept 1981-Dec 1981; Jan 1982; Feb-Dec 1982
  - Irish People (New York), 1981-1985; cuid14678 (Box 192)
  - Irish People (New York), 1983-1985; cuid14681 (Box 87, Box 88, Box 89, Box 90, Box 91)
  - Irish People (New York), 1986; cuid14686 (Box 193, Box 92, Box 93, Box 94)
  - Irish People (New York), 1986-1991; cuid14690 (Box 188)
  - Irish People (New York), 1987-1990; cuid14691 (Box 95, Box 219, Folder 3, Box 222, Folder 4)
    Feb 1987-Oct 1987 (with gaps); April 2 1988; Apr 23, 1988; Jan 27 1990; Jun 30, 1990; Dec 15, 1990
  - Irish People (New York), 1991-1994; cuid14692 (Box 96, Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100)
  - Irish People (New York), 1992-1995; cuid14693 (Box 189)
  - Irish People (New York), 1995-1999; cuid14698 (Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Box 104, Box 105, Box 106, Box 190, Box 208, Folder 2)
  - Irish People (New York), 2000-2004; cuid14704 (Box 191)
  - Irish People (New York), 2001-2002; cuid14705 (Box 107, Box 108, Box 109, Box 110, Box 111, Box 112)
  - Irish People (New York), 2003-2004; cuid14711 (Box 113, Box 114, Box 115)
    2003; Feb 2004-Aug 2004
  - The Irish Press, Nov 23, 1963; cuid14714 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - The Irish Prisoner, Feb-Mar 1980 (Box 220, Folder 17)
  - Irish Post: The Voice of the Irish in Britain (London), Jun 1985–Sep 1987; cuid14715 (Box 145)
  - Irish Rebel (Friends of Irish Freedom, Boston), Vol 1, No. 1, Nov 1969; cuid14716 (Box 149)
  - Irish Star, March 1985 (Box 220, Folder 9)
  - The Irish Times, 1998, 2016, 2018 (Box 220, Folder 11)
  - The Irish World and Industrial Liberator, Jun 1943-Aug 1943; cuid14746 (Box Shared Tamiment 149, Folder 9)
  - Irish World, 1968-1984 (Box 222, Folder 5-8)
    Apr 13 1968; May 4 1968; Oct 30 1971; Mar 11 1972; Mar 18 1972; Mar 25 1972; Mar 10 1973; Mar 17 1973; July 28 1973; Sept 1 1973; Feb 9 1974; Mar 30 1974; June 15 1974; Sept 20 1975; Mar 20 1976; Dec 4 1976; Dec 25 1976; Jan 22 1977; Feb 12 1977; Feb 19 1977; Feb 26 1977; Feb 17 1979; Mar 24 1979; Oct 11 1980; Oct 18 1980; Mar 6 1982; Oct 9 1982; Dec 18 1982; Feb 5 1983; April 9 1983; Oct 1 1983; Jan 21 1984; May 5 1984
  - Irish World, 1971-1981; cuid14747 (Box 141)
    Oct 23, 1971; Feb 2, 1974-Mar 30, 1974; May 17, 1975; Feb 10, 1979; Jan 5, 1980–Dec 20, 1980; Jan 10, 1981–Mar 28, 1981 [Vol. 102, No. 5288, Vol. 104, Nos. 5407 – 5409, 5413-5415, Vol. 105, No. 5494, Vol. 109, No. 5689, Vol. 110, Nos. 5732-5782 (Missing 5741,5754), Vol. 111, Nos. 5785-5796 (Missing 5794)]
  - Irish World, 1981-1984; cuid14748 (Box 142, Box 143, Box 220, Folder 4)
    Apr 4, 1981–Dec 26, 1981; Jan 2, 1982–Dec 25, 1982 [Vol. 111, Nos. 5797-5837 (Missing 5801-5803,5814,5823), Vol. 112, Nos. 5838-5889 (Missing 5879)]; Jan 1, 1983–Dec 24, 1983; Jan 7, 1984–Nov 17, 1984 [Vol. 113, Nos. 5890-5941 (Missing 5908,5937), Vol. 114, Nos. 5932-5985 (Missing 5962,5968,5973-5975,5983)]
  - Irish World (BRITTLE), July 30, 1983 (Box 222, Folder 9)
  - Liberty, Mar 2016 (Box 221, Folder 6)
  - National Hibernian Digest, Jan 1974–May 1984; cuid14750 (Box 156)
  - National Hibernian Digest, 1978-2016 (Box 220, Folder 1-3)
    May-Jun 1978; Juy-Aug 1985; Sept-Dec 1990; July-Aug 1996; Mar-April 1998; Jan-Feb 2004; Nov-Dec 2005; Sept-Oct 2010; Mar-April 2011; Jan-Feb 2015; Sept-Dec 2015; Mar-Apr 2016
  - National Hibernian Digest (with gaps), 1989, 2001-2011; cuid14751 (Box 184)
  - National Museum of Ireland, undated (Box 221, Folder 5)
  - New York Times, 1862, 1995; cuid14752 (Box Shared Tamiment 149, Folder 8)
  - The Phoenix (New York), 1859-1861; cuid14753 (Box 185, Reel R-7943)
    Existence and Location of Copies